好，今天，我想更多地讨论一些
all right today I want to talk about bit
关于容错和复制的问题
more about fault tolerance and
然后深入研究
replication and then look into the
今天的关于 VMware 容错的论文的详细内容
details of today's paper about vmware ft
话题回到容错上来
the topics still fault tolerance to
容错以提供高可用性————
provide high availability that is you
例如：当你想构建一个服务器时
want to build a server that even if some
提供服务的硬件总是有崩溃的可能
hardware you know computer crashes is
但是
involved in the service we still like to
我们还是希望能稳定地提供服务
provide the service and to the extent we
甚至，我们想（并且可以）在即使出现了网络问题的时候
can we'd like to provide our service
依旧提供我们的服务————
also if there's network problems and the
我们所使用到的工具就是“复制”
tool we're using its replication least
至少在本课程的这一部分是这样
for this part of the course so it's
一个很有价值的问题：
worth asking what kind of failures
复制能处理什么样的“失败”呢？
replication can be expected to deal with
因为这无论如何都不是一件小事
because it's not everything by any means
使用最简单的方法来描述一下
so maybe the easiest way to characterize
我们所能处理的那种“失败”————
the kind of failures we're talking about
那就是单个计算机的“停止-失败”
is fail stop failures of a single
我所谓的“停止-失败”是什么呢？
computer and what I mean by fail stop
其实是一种通用的术语
it's a sort of generic term and fault
容错就是说如果有一些东西出了故障
tolerance is that if something goes
比如说一台计算机出了什么问题
wrong would say the computer the
它就会简单地停止运行
computer simply stops executing it just
如果任何东西出了什么故障的话
stops if anything goes wrong and in
尤其需要注意的是：它不会计算出不正确的结果
particular it doesn't compute incorrect
所以，如果有人断了你的电源
results so if somebody kicks the power
把电源线从你的服务器上拔了出来
cable out of your server that's probably
那就有可能产生一个“停止-失败”
gonna generate a fail stop failure
类似地，如果他们拔了你的服务器的网络插头
similarly if they unplug your servers
这也是一个“停止-失败”
network connection even though the
尽管你知道服务器仍在运行
server is still running so this is a
所以这就有点可笑
little bit funny you know be totally cut
因为对于网络另一头的我来说
off from the network so it looks at me
服务器断了网就和停止运行没啥两样
outside like it just stopped so it's
所以这些错误是我们可以处理的错误
really these failures we can deal with
复制能处理的问题也包括一些硬件问题
with replication this also covers some
比如
hardware problems like you know maybe if
你的服务器的风扇坏了
the fan on your server breaks because it
可能因为太便宜了，哈哈
you know it cost 50 cents maybe that'll
这就有可能使 CPU 过热
cause the CPU to overheat and the CPU
然后 CPU 就停止运行了
will shut itself down cleanly and just
干净利落
stop executing
我们所讨论的这种复制系统
what's not covered by the kind of
也有一些它不能处理的问题
replication systems we're talking about
比如软件问题、软件漏洞
is things like bugs and software or
或者一些更基本的、不是软件漏洞的硬件设计缺陷
design defects in hardware so basically
如果我们接受一些服务
not bugs because if we take some service
假如说，你有一台 MapReduce master 主机
you know say you're a MapReduce master
我们复制运行它
for example you know we replicated and
我们在两台计算机上复制运行它
run it on two computers you know if
如果你的 MapReduce master 有一个漏洞
there's a bug in your MapReduce master
或者我的 MapReduce master 有一个漏洞
or my MapReduce master let's say
那么复制对我们没有任何帮助
replications not going to help us we're
我们还是会得到计算错误的结果
going to compute the same incorrect
在两台 MapReduce master 主机上都是这样
result on both of our copies of our
并且从表面上看一切都好好的
MapReduce master and everything looked
它们会默默允许让你碰上一个错误答案
fine they'll agree you just happen to be
所以
the wrong answer so we can't depending
我们不能依赖于复制软件中的漏洞
against bugs in the replicated software
并且
and we can't defend against bugs in the
我们管理复制的方案中的漏洞也是不可防御的
whatever scheme we're using to manage
和我刚才提到的类似
the replication and similarly as I
我们不能期望处理硬件中的漏洞
mentioned before we can't expect to deal
这个硬件呢
with bugs in the hardware the hardware
它会计算出不正确的结果
it computes incorrectly that's just
事情也就这样了
that's the end for us at least with this
至少对于这种技术来说，也就如此了
kind of technique although you know that
尽管肯定有一些硬件和软件漏洞
said there are definitely hardware and
是复制能解决的
software bugs that that replication
如果你足够幸运的话
might if you're lucky might be able to
如果
cope it so if there's some unrelated
有一些不相关的软件运行在你的服务器上
software running in your server and it
它使你的服务器崩溃了
causes the server to crash maybe because
或者可能使你的 kernel 出现 panic 并重启
your kernel to panic and reboot or
或者什么也不做
something it has nothing to do with you
对你正复制的服务什么也不做
know with your with the service you're
那么
replicating then that kind of failure
这种错误对于我们的服务来说
for us for your service will may well be
就是一种“停止-失败”
fail stop
你懂的，kernel 将会 panic
you know the kernel will panic and the
并且备份复制会取而代之
backup replicas will take over similarly
有一些种类的硬件错误
some kinds of hardware errors can be
可以被转化为“停止-失败”错误
turned into fail stop errors for example
例如：如果你通过网络发送了一个包
if you send a packet over the network
但是网络损坏了这个包，它翻转了一个比特位
and the network corrupts it just flips a
像这种情况
bit in your packet that will almost
几乎肯定可以通过校验和而检测出来
certainly be caught by the checksum on
一个磁盘块也是一样的
the packet same thing for a disk block
如果你往磁盘上写了一些数据
if you write some data to disk and read
然后一个月后又把它读出来
it back a month later you know maybe the
也许磁表面不是很完美
magnetic surface isn't perfect and you
在这个块上，最重要的那几个比特位是错的
know one of the best couple of bits were
但是它能被正确地读出来
wrong in the block as it's right back
这实际上是纠错功能
it's actually error correcting
能在一定程度上
that up to a certain point will fix
修复磁盘块中地错误
errors in disk blocks that you'll be
这样的话
turning you know random hardware errors
一些随机的硬件错误可以被纠正
into as either correcting them if you're
如果你超级幸运的话
super lucky or at least detecting them
或者至少可以检测到错误
and turning random corruption into a
从而让软件知道
detected fault which you know the
知道发生了错误
software then knows that something that
从而可以把硬件错误转化为一个“停止-失败”错误
wrong and can turn it into a fail stop
即时地停止运行或者采取一些其他的补救措施
fault by stopping executing or take some
但是，一般来说
other remedial action but in general we
我们只能期望去处理一些“停止-失败”错误
really can only expect to handle fail
复制还有一些其他的限制
stop faults there's other limits to
啊，其他限制
replication to you know the the failures
不管失败发生在主要的那个复制中
in the if we have a primary in the back
还是发生在备份的那个复制中或者其他怎样
of our two replicas or whatever we're
我们总是假设
really assuming that failures in the two
两个复制中的失败是相互独立的
are independent right if there tend to
如果两个复制中总是有相关联的失败
have correlated failures then
那么，复制将对我们没有帮助
replication is not going to help us so
例如，如果我们有一整套设备
for example if we're a big outfit and we
我们买了成千上万的计算机
buy thousands of computers batches of
啊，成千上万台计算机
thousands of computers identical
同一家厂商生产的成千上万的相同的计算机
computers from the same manufacturer and
我们把我们的复制运行在上面
we run you know our replicas is on all
我们一次在同一个地方买那么多电脑
on those computers we bought at the same
这可有一点风险
time from the same place that's a bit of
啊，有点风险
a risk
因为很可能
maybe because presumably if one of them
其中一个有了缺陷
has a manufacturing defect in it there's
其他的也有相同的缺陷
a good chance that the other ones do too
比如说
you know one of them's prone to
由于制造商没有设计好散热系统
overheating because the manufacturer you
导致其中的一个过热了
know didn't provide enough airflow well
那么很有可能这一批货都有这个问题
it probably all had that problem and so
所以如果其中一个过热、宕机了
one of them overheats and dies it's a
那么其他的也很有可能同样宕机
good chance that the other ones will too
这是相关失败的一种
so that's one kind of correlated failure
你要小心的是另一种
you just have to be careful of another
比如说
one is that you know if there's an
地震了
earthquake and the city where our
地震正好发生在存储着我们的数据的数据中心所在的城市
datacenter is probably gonna take out
在这种情况下
the whole data center you know we can
无论我们在那个数据中心里弄多少复制
have all the replication we like inside
也无济于事
that data center it's not going to help
因为这种失败
us because the failure caused by an
这种由地震、全市停电引起的失败
earthquake or a citywide power failure
或者建筑失火这种
or something the building burning down
它是相关失败
is like it's correlated failure between
同一建筑内的复制之间的相关失败
our replicas if they're on that building
所以如果我们想处理地震带来的问题
so if we care about dealing with
那么
earthquakes then we need to put our
我们需要把我们的复制放在不同的城市
replicas in maybe in just different
至少把它们在物理上足够分隔开
cities at least physically separate
让它们分别供电
enough that they have separate power
这样它们就不会被同一自然灾害所影响了
unlikely to be affected by the same
对，不会
natural disaster
好了，这就是全部种类的不稳定性了
okay but that's all sort of hovering in
至少在我们这次讨论的背景下
the background for this discussion where
我们所讨论的正是你可能会使用的技术
we're talking about the technology you
还有一个关于复制的问题
might use another question about
你可能会问你自己
replication is whether it's worthwhile
天呐
you may ask yourself gosh you know this
使用 2 倍甚至 3 倍计算机资源的复制方案，这真的值得吗
literally uses these replication schemes
use twice as much or three times as much
对了
computer resources right we need to have
我们需要让 GFS 的每一个 block 都有三份拷贝的话
you know GFS had three copies of every
我们就得买三倍容量的磁盘
blocks we have to buy three times as much
啊，今天的那篇论文呢
disk space the paper for today
只复制了一次
you know replicates just once but that
但是那意味着我们有两倍的计算机、CPU 和 RAM
means we have twice as many computers
这些东西都是很昂贵的
and CPUs and RAM it's all for expensive
这真的很值得吗
like is that really worth it that
并且
expense and you know that's not
这不是一个我们能从技术上回答正确的问题
something we can answer technically
这是一个经济上的问题
right it's an economic question it
这个问题取决于获取一个可用的服务的价值
depends on the value of having an
available service you know if you're
比如说你在运行一个银行服务
running a bank and if the consequence is
计算机宕机的后果就是
the computer failing is that your
你不能服务你的顾客了
customer you can't serve your customers
你也就不能获得收入了
and you can't generate revenue and your
你的顾客们也会恨你
customers all hate you then it may well
权衡之下，多花一两万在一台备份计算机上很可能是值得的
be worth it to blow you know an extra
ten or twenty thousand bucks on a second
所以，你可以复制一份
computer so you can have a replica on
另一方面，假如你是我，你在运行维护 6.824 的网站服务器
the other hand if you're me and you're
running the 6.824 web server I don't
我觉得不值得给 6.824 网站做热备份
consider it worthwhile to have a hot
backup of the 84 web server because the
因为运行失败所造成的后果没什么大不了的
consequences of failure are very low so
复制是否值得？
the whether the replication is
该复制多少份？
worthwhile on how many replicas you
这都取决于
ought to have and how much you're
你愿意花费多少在这上面
willing to spend on it is all about how
取决于当失败发生时会给你带来多大的损失和不便
much cost and inconvenience failure
好了
would call it cause you all right this
开头提到的这篇论文
paper sort of in the beginning mentions
介绍了几种不同的复制方法
as there's a couple of different
啊，其实介绍了两种
approaches to replication really
一种叫做 状态转移
mentions two one two calls state
另一种叫做 复制状态机
transfer and the other calls replicated
在这个班上呢
state machine most of the schemes we're
我们主要讨论复制状态机
going to talk about in this class are
replicated state machines
但我们也会讨论状态转移的
it'll talk about both anyway the idea
状态转移背后的思想是
behind state transferor's that if we
如果我们有一个服务器的两份复制
have two replicas of a server the way
你让它们保持同步的方式就是
you cause them to be to stay in sync
让它们成为实际上的复制
that is to be actual replicas so that
使备份拥有它需要的一切
the backup can has everything it needs
以便当主机宕机时备份能够接管
to take over if the primary fails in a
在一个状态转移模式中
state transfer scheme the way that works
它工作的方式就是，主机发送一份整个自身状态的拷贝
is that the primary sends a copy of its
比如
entire state that is for example the
它内存的内容，把它发送给备份
contents of its RAM to the backup and
备份只是存储最新的状态
the backup just sort of stores the
这样，备份就有全部的主机状态
latest state and so it's all there
主机如果宕机了的话
the primary fails in the backup can
备份就可以开始运行在最新状态
start executing with this last state it
如果主机宕机了的话
got if the primary fails so this is all
所以这完全就是发送主机的状态
about sending the state of the of the
今天
primary and for today's if today's paper
如果今天的论文以一个状态转移系统来运行的话
worked as a state transfer system which
其实并不是
it doesn't then the state we'd be
我们所讨论的状态就是 RAM 里的内容
talking about would be the contents of
主机的内存里的内容
the RAM the contents of the memory of
所以
the primary so maybe every once while
可能每次主机复制了一大份拷贝
the primary would just you know make a
一大份自身内存的拷贝并且发送的时候
big copy of its memory and send it
需要通过网络发送给备份
across the network to the backup you can
imagine if you wanted to be efficient
you know maybe you would only send the
parts of the memory that it's changed
since the last time you sent in memory
to the backup the replicated state
machine
this approach observes that most
services are most computer things we
want to replicate have some internal
确定性的操作
operation that's deterministic except
除非外部输入到来
when external input comes in right
通常情况下，如果计算机没有外部影响
ordinarily if there's no external
influences on a computer
它只是一个接一个地执行指令
it just executes one instruction after another
每条指令做的是
and what each instruction does is a
一个计算机内存和寄存器中内容的确定性函数
deterministic function of what's in the
memory and the registers of the computer
而且只有当外部事件干预时，才可能发生意外情况
and it's only when external events intervene
that something unexpected may happen
像是某个随机时间到达的数据包
like a packet arrives of a some random time
导致服务器开始做些不一样的事
and that causes the server
to start doing something differently
复制的状态机方案不会在副本之间发送状态
so replicated state machine schemes
don't send the state between the replicas
相反，他们只是发送这些外部事件
instead they just send those
external events they just send maybe
只是从primary发送到backup
from a primary to a backup again
只是发送backup需要了解的信息，例如从外界获取的输入
just send things like arriving input from the
outside world that the backup needs to
只是发送backup需要了解的信息，例如从外界获取的输入
know about
观察结果是
and the observation is that
如果有两台计算机
if there are two computers and they start
并且它们从相同的状态开始
from the same state and they see the
并且它们以相同的顺序或相同的时间看到相同的输入
same inputs in the same order
or at the same time the two computers
则两台计算机将继续互为彼此的复制
will continue to be replicas of each
并以相同的方式执行
other and sort of execute identically
只要他们俩同时看到相同的输入
as long as they both see the same inputs at the same time
这可能转移了内存
so this transfers probably memory
这传递给primary和backup
and this transfer some primary backup
来自client的操作或外部输入或外部事件
just operations from clients or
external external inputs or external events
人们倾向于使用复制状态机的原因
and the reason why
people tend to favor a replicated state machine
在于通常操作要比状态小
is that usually operations are
smaller than the state but this
服务器的状态，如果是数据库服务器
the state of a server if it's a database
可能是整个数据库
server might be the entire database
可能是千兆字节
might be gigabytes whereas the
而操作只是一些客户端发送的
operations are just some clients sending
比如，请读写key27
please read or write key 27
操作通常很小
operations are usually small the states
状态通常很大
usually large so replicate a state
因此复制状态机通常看起来很吸引人
machine usually looks attractive and
轻微的缺点是这些方案往往要复杂得多
slight downside is that the schemes tend
to be quite a bit more complicated and
并且依赖于计算机运行方式的更多假设
rely on sort of more assumptions about
how the computers operate whereas
然而这种方案则简单粗暴
this is a really heavy-handed
我只是要寄给你 我的整个状态
I'm just gonna send you my whole state sort of a
没什么要担心的
nothing to worry about
关于这些策略，有什么问题吗
any questions about these strategies yes
好吧，所以问题是
well ok so the question is
假设我们的方案出了点问题
suppose something went wrong with our scheme
backup实际上与primary不一样
and the backup was not actually
identical to the primary so
假设我们正在运行一个GFS master服务器
suppose we were running a GFS master
这是master
and it's the primary it just
它刚刚将租约分发给了chunk服务器一
handed out a lease to chunks server one
但是因为
but because the two because
因为因为我们允许primary和backup节点的状态不同步
we've allowed the states of the primary
back to drift out of sync
备份没有向任何人发出租约
the backup did not issue a lease to anybody
甚至没有意识到有人请求租约
or even aware anybody had asked for lease
现在primary服务器认为chunk服务器持有某些块的租约
so now the primary thinks
chunks server one has lease for some chunk
而backup并没有，primary服务器失败
the backup doesn't the primary fails
backup接手 现在chunk服务器一
backup takes over right now chunks server
认为它持有某些块的租约
one thinks it has a lease for some chunk
但是当前的primary服务器不知道
but then the current master doesn't and
并且很乐意将租约分发给其他chunk服务器
is happy to hand out the lease to some
现在我们有两个chunk服务器提供相同的租约
other chunk server now we have two chunk
servers serving the same lease okay so
那只是一个接近家庭的例子
that's just a close to home example
但实际上几乎所有坏事
but really almost any bad thing and
我认为你可以构造任何坏的情况
kind of I think you construct any bad
想象某些服务会因为状态不同，导致计算出错误答案
scenario by just imagining some service
that conpute the wrong answer because
想象某些服务会因为状态不同，导致计算出错误答案
the state's diverge
你问了随机化的问题
so you're asking about randomization
是的，哦，你们都在谈论这个
yeah oh y'all talk about this I'll talk
我待会儿再说
about this a bit later on but it is good
当primary和backup正在执行的相同的指令时
that the replicated state scheme
definitely makes the most sense when the
复制状态机方案绝对是最有意义的
instructions that the primary and
backup are executing do the same thing
只要没有外部事件
as long as there's no external events
这对于add指令之类的东西几乎是正确的
right and that's almost true right
for an add instruction or something
是的
yeah if the starting if the
如果它们的寄存器和存储器都相同
registers and memory of the same and they
并且它们都执行一条add指令
both execute an add instruction add instruction
那么add指令在相同的输出中具有相同的输入
has the same inputs in
the same outputs but they're in some
但是在某些指令中
instructions as you point out that don't
正如你指出的那样
like maybe there's an instruction that
比如一条获取当前时间的指令可以
gets the current time of day now
可能会在略有不同的时间执行
probably be executed at slightly
different times or an instruction that
或者获得当前处理器唯一ID
gets the current processors unique ID
和序列号的指令将产生不同的答案
and a serial number it's going to yield
different answers
这些问题的统一的答案
and the uniform answered the questions that
是primary执行指令
sound like this is that the primary does it
并将答案发送给backup
and sends the answer to the backup
backup不执行该指令
and the backup does not execute that instruction
但是在执行该指令的地方
but instead at the point
where it would execute that instruction
它会听从primary
it listens for the primary to tell it
告诉它正确的答案是什么
what the right answer would be and just
只是伪造了答案给软件
sort of fakes that answer to the software
我将讨论VMware方案如何做到这一点
I'll talk about how
the VMware scheme does that okay
有趣的是
interestingly enough though
今天的论文都是关于复制状态机的
today's paper is all about a replicated state machine
你可能已经注意到
you may have noticed that
今天的论文仅涉及单处理器
today's paper only deals with uni-processors
而且还不清楚如何将其扩展到多核机器
and it's not that clear how
it could be extended to a multi-core and
在多核机器中
a multi-core machine where the
两个核的指令的交织是不确定的
interleavings of the instructions from
the two cores are
两个核的指令的交织是不确定的
non-deterministic
因此，我们不再在多核计算机上出现这种情况
so we no longer have this situation on a
因为如果让主数据库和备份计算机执行，
multi-core machine where if we just let
其他条件都相同，
the primary and backup execute they're
那么它们将是相同的
all else being equal they're
going to be the same because they won't
因为它们不会在多核计算机上执行
execute on multiple cores
VMware之后推出了一个可能完全不同的新复制系统
VMware has since come out with a new possibly
completely different replication system
该系统可以在多核上运行
that does work on multi-core
在我看来，新系统使用状态转移而不是复制状态机
and the new system appears to me to be using state transfer
instead of replicated state machine
因为面对多核和并行性，状态转移更加健壮
because state transferred is
more robust in the face of
因为面对多核和并行性，状态转移更加健壮
multi-core and parallelism
如果您使用机器并将内存发送过来
if you use the machine and send the memory over
内存映像只是机器的状态而已
that the memory image is just that
just is the state of the machine and
并行性并不影响
sort of it doesn't matter that there was
parallelism whereas the replicated state
而复制状态机方案确实存在并行性问题
machine scheme really has a problem with
the parallelism
另一方面，我猜想这种新的多核方案会更昂贵
on the other hand I'm guessing that this new
multi-core scheme is more expensive okay
好的，如果我们要构建一个复制状态机方案
all right so if we want to build a
replicated state machine scheme we got a
我们有很多问题要回答
number of questions to answer
我们需要决定要在什么级别上复制状态
so we need to decide at what level we're gonna
replicate state right so what state
我们所说的状态是什么
what do we mean by state we have to worry
我们必须担心primary和backup之间紧密同步的程度
about how closely synchronized the
primary and backup have to be right
因为primary可能领先backup执行一些
because it's likely the primary will
execute a little bit ahead of the backup
毕竟，是primary看到输入
after all it it's the primary that sees the inputs
因此备份几乎必须滞后于
so the backup almost
necessarily must lag over that gives
这意味着有可能primary出现故障
that means there's an opportunity if the
primary fails for the
且backup没能完全追上primary
backup not to be fully caught up
使backup与primary完全同步执行实际上是昂贵的
having the backup actually executes really in
lockstep with the primaries is expensive
因为需要很多时间
because it requires a lot of chitchat
因此，很多设计
so a lot of designs a lot of
人们担心的是同步有多紧密
what people sweat about is how close the synchronization is
如果primary发生故障
if the primary fails
或者您实际上知道backup是否也失败
or you know actually if the backup fails too
但是如果primary发生故障则更令人兴奋
but it's more exciting if the primary fails
必须有一些切换方案
there has to be some scheme for
客户端必须知道
switching over and the clients have to know
哦，天哪，我现在不应该与服务器一上的旧primary通信
oh gosh I instead of talking to the
old primary on server one I should now
我现在应该与服务器二上的backup服务器通信
be talking to the
the backup on server two all the clients
所有客户端都必须以某种方式解决此问题
have to somehow figure this out
切换几乎可以肯定
the switch over almost certainly it's almost
几乎不可能设计一个
impossible maybe impossible to design a
不会出现任何异常现象的切入系统
cut over system in which no anomalies
are ever visible
在这种理想的世界中
in this sort of ideal world
如果primary失败，没有人注意到
if the primary fails we'd like nobody to ever notice
没有client注意到
none of the clients to notice turns out
这基本上是无法实现的
that's basically unattainable
所以在切入过程中会出现异常
so there's going to be anomalies during the cut over
我们必须找出一种应对它们的方法
and we've gotta figure out a way to
cope with them and finally if the one of
如果我们的复制之一失败了
the two if one of our replicas fails
我们真的需要一个新的复制
we really need to have a new replica right
如果我们有两个复制，其中一个失败
if we have a two replicas and one fails
我们只是靠借来的时间生活
we're just living on borrowed time right
因为第二个复制可能在某个时候失败
because the second replica may fail at some point
因此，我们绝对需要使新复制尽快上线
so we absolutely need to get
a new replica back online as fast as possible
那可能很昂贵
so and that can be very
状态很大
expensive the state is big
但是我们喜欢复制状态机的原因是
but the reason we like to replicate
因为我们认为状态转移会很昂贵
a state machine was because we thought
state transfer would be expensive but
但复制状态机中的两个复制仍需要具有完整状态
the two replicas in a replicated state
machine still need to have full state right
我们只是有一种便宜的方法来使它们保持同步
we just had a cheap way of keeping
如果我们需要创建新复制的话
them both in sync if we need to create a
实际上我们别无选择
new replica we actually have no choice
只能进行状态转移以创建新的复制
but state transfer to create the new replicas
新复制需要具有状态的完整状态
the new replica needs to have a
complete copy of the state
因此创建新复制将非常昂贵
so it's going to be expensive to create new replicas
人们通常会花费很多
and this is often people spending well
实际上人们花很多时间担心所有这些问题
actually people spend a lot of time
worrying about all these questions and
我们在查看其他复制状态机方案时会再次看到它们
we'll see them again as we look
at other replicated state machine schemes
所以关于什么状态要复制的话题
so on the topic of what state to replicate
今天的论文对这个问题有一个非常有趣的答案
the today's paper has a very
interesting answer to this question
它复制了机器的完整状态
it replicates the full state of the machine
即所有内存和所有机器寄存器
that is all of memory and all the
Machine registers it's like a very very
是一个非常详细的复制方案
detailed replication scheme
primary和backup，即使是最底层，也完全一样
just no difference at the even of the lowest
levels between the primary and the backup
对于复制方案而言，这是非常罕见的
that's quite rare for replication
schemes
比如说GFS
almost always you see something that's
GFS当然
more like GFS where GFS absolutely did
not replicate you know they had
replication but it wasn't replicating
every single you know bit of memory
between the primaries and the backups
it was replicating much more application
level table of chunks
I had this abstraction of you know
chunks and chunk identifiers and that's
what it was replicating it wasn't
replicating sort of everything else
wasn't going to the expense of
replicating every single other thing
in that machines we're doing okay as long
as they had the same sort of application
visible set of chunks so most
replication schemes out there go the GFS
route in fact almost everything except
pretty much this paper and a few handful
of similar systems almost everything
uses application at some level
application level of replication because
it can be much more efficient because we
don't have to go to the we don't have to
go to the trouble of for example making
sure that interrupts occur at exactly
the same point in the execution of the
primary and backup GFS does not sweat
that at all but this paper has to do
because it replicates at such a low
level so most people build efficient
systems with applications specific
replication the consequence of that
though is that the replication has to be
built into the right into the
application right if you're getting a
feed of application level operations for
example you really need to have the
application participate in that because
some generic replication thing like
today's paper
doesn't really can't understand the
semantics of what needs to be replicated
so anyway so most teams are application
specific like GFS and every other paper
we're going to read on this topic
today's paper is unique in that it
replicates at the level of the machine
and therefore does not care what
software you run on it right it
replicates the low-level memory and
machine registers you can run any
software you like on it as long as it
runs on that kind of microprocessor
that's being represented this
replication scheme applies to the
software can be anything
and you know the downside is that it's
not that efficient necessarily the
upside is that you can take any existing
piece of software maybe you don't even
have source code for it or understand
how it works and you know do within some
limits you can just run it under this
under VMware's replication scheme and
it'll just work which is sort of magic
fault-tolerance wand for arbitrary
software all right now let me talk about
how this is VMware FT first of all
VMware is a virtual machine company
they're what their business is a lot of
their business is selling virtual
machine technology and what virtual
machines refer to is the idea of you
know you buy a single computer and
instead of booting an operating system
like Linux on the hardware you boot
we'll call a virtual machine monitor or
hypervisor on the hardware and the
hypervisor's job is actually to
simulate multiple multiple computers
multiple virtual computers on this piece
of hardware so the virtual machine
monitor may boot up you know one
instance of Linux may be multiple
instances of Linux may be a Windows
machine you can the virtual machine
monitor on this one computer can run a
bunch of different operating systems you
know each of these as is itself some
sort of operating system kernel and then
applications so this is the technology
they're starting with and you know the
reason for this is that if you know you
need to it just turns out there's many
many reasons why it's very convenient to
kind of interpose this level of
indirection between the hardware and the
operating systems and means that we can
buy one computer and run lots of
different operating systems on it we can
have each if we run lots and lots of
little services instead of having to
have lots and lots of computers one per
service you can just buy one computer
and run each service in the operating
system that it needs I'm using these
virtual machines so this was their
starting point they already had this
stuff and a lot of sophisticated things
built around it at the start of
designing vmware ft so this is just
virtual machines um what the paper's
doing is that it's gonna set up one
machine or they did requires two
physical machines because there's no
point in running the primary and backup
software in different virtual machines
on the same physical machine because
we're trying to guard against hardware
failures so you're gonna to at least you
know you have two machines running their
virtual machine monitors and the primary
is going to run on one, the backup is on
the other so on one of these machines we
have a guest you know we only it might
be running a lot of virtual machines we
only care about one of them it's gonna
be running some guest operating system
and some sort of server application
maybe a database server, MapReduce master,
or something so I'll call this the
primary and there'll be a second machine
that you know runs the same virtual
machine monitor and an identical virtual
machine holding the backup so we have
the same whatever the operating system
is exactly the same and the virtual
machine is you know giving these guest
operating systems the primary and backup
a each range of memory and this memory
images will be identical or the goal is
to make them identical in the primary in
the backup we have two physical machines
each one of them running a virtual
machine guest with its own copy of the
service we care about we're assuming
that there's a network connecting these
two machines and in addition on this
local area network in addition on this
network there's some set of clients
really, they don't have to be clients
they're just maybe other computers that
our replicated service needs to talk
with some of them are clients
sending requests it turns out in this
paper there the replicated service
actually doesn't use a local disk and
instead assumes that there's some sort
of disk server that it talks to him
although it's a little bit hard to
realize this from the paper the scheme
actually does not really treat the
server particularly especially it's just
another external source of packets and
place that the replicated state machine
may send packets to not very much
different from clients okay so the basic
scheme is that the we assume that these
two replicas, the two virtual machines,
primary and backup, are exact
replicas some client, you know database
client who knows who has some client of
our replicated server sends a request to
the primary and that really takes the
form of a network packet that's what
we're talking about that generates an
interrupt
and this interrupt actually goes to the
virtual machine monitor at least in the
first instance the virtual machine
monitor sees here's the input for
this replicated service and so the
virtual machine monitor does two things
one is it sort of simulates a network
packet arrival interrupt into the
primary guest operating system to
deliver it to the primary copy of the
application and in addition the virtual
machine monitor you know knows that this
is an input to a replicated virtual
machine and it's so it sends back out on
the network a copy of that packet to the
backup virtual machine monitor it also
gets it and backup virtual machine
monitor knows ha it is a packet for this
particular replicated state machine and
it also fakes a sort of network packet
arrival interrupt at the backup and
delivers the packet so now both the
primary and the backup have a copy this
packet they looks at, the same input you
know with a lot of details are gonna
process it in the same way and stay
synchronized
course the service is probably going to
reply to the client on the primary the
service will generate a reply packet and
send it on the NIC that the virtual
machine monitor is emulating and then
the virtual machine monitor will
we'll see that output packet on the
primary they'll actually send the reply
back out on the network to the client
because the backup is running exactly
the same sequence of instructions it
also generates a reply packet back to
the client and sends that reply packet
on its emulated NIC it's the virtual
machine monitor that's emulating that
network interface card and it says aha
you know the virtual machine monitor
says I know this was the backup only the
primary is allowed to generate output
and the virtual machine monitor drops
the reply packet so both of them see
inputs and only the primary generates
outputs as far as terminology goes the
paper calls this stream of input events
and other things, other events we'll talk
about from the stream is called the
logging Channel it all goes over the
same network presumably but these events
the primary send to the backup are called
log events on the log Channel
where the fault tolerance comes in is
that those the primary crashes what the
backup is going to see is that it stops
getting stuff on the stops getting log
entries a log entry stops getting log
entries on the logging channel and we
know it it turns out that the backup can
expect to get many per second because
one of the things that generates log
entries is periodic timer interrupts in
the in the primary each one of which
turns out every interrupt generates a
log entries into the backup these timer
interrupts are going to happen like 100
times a second so the backups can
certainly expect to see
a lot of chitchat on the logging Channel
if the primaries up if the primary
crashes then the virtual machine
monitored over here will say gosh you
know I haven't received anything on the
logging channel for like a second or
however long the primary must be dead or
or something and in that case when the
backup stop seeing log entries from the
primary the paper the way the paper
phrases it is that the backup goes live
and what that means is that it stops
waiting for these input events on the
logging Channel from the primary and
instead this virtual machine monitor
just lets this backup execute freely
without waiting for without being driven
by input events from the primary the vmm
does something to the network to cause
future client requests to go to the
backup instead of the primary and the
VMM here stops discarding the backup
personnel it's the primary not the
backup stops discarding output from this
virtual machine so now this or machine
directly gets the inputs and there's a
lot of produce output and now our backup
is taken over and similarly you know
that this is less interesting but has to
work correctly
if the backup fails a similar primary
has to use a similar process to abandon
the backup stop sending it events and
just sort of act much more like a single
non replicated server so either one of
them can go live if the other one
appears to be dead stops you know stops
generating network traffic
magic now it depends you know depends on
what the networking technology is I
think with the paper one possibility is
that this is sitting on Ethernet every
physical computer on the Internet or
really every NIC has a 48 bit unique ID
I'm making this up now the it could be
that in fact instead of each physical
computer having a unique ID each virtual
machine does and when the backup takes
over it essentially claims the primary's
Ethernet ID as its own and it starts
saying you know I'm the owner of that ID
and then other people on the ethernet
will start sending us packets that's my
interpretation the designers believed
they had identified all such sources and
for each one of them the primary does
whatever it is you know executes the
random number generator instruction or
takes an interrupt at some time the
backup does not and the back of virtual
machine monitor sort of detects any such
instruction and and intercepts that and
doesn't do it and he said the backup
waits for an event on the logging
Channel saying this instruction number
you know the random number was whatever
it was on the primary
At which?
yes yes
yeah the paper hints that they got Intel
to add features to the microprocessor to
support exactly this but they don't say
what it was okay
okay so on that topic the so far that
you know the story is sort of assumed
that as long as the backup to sees the
package from the clients it'll execute
in identically to the primary and that's
actually glossing over some huge and
important details so one problem is that
as a couple of people have mentioned
there are some things that are
non-deterministic now it's not the case
that every single thing that happens in
the computer is a deterministic function
of the contents of the memory of the
computer it is for a sort of straight
line code execution often but certainly
not always so worried about is things
that may happen that are not a strict
function of the current state that is
that might be different if we're not
careful on the primary and backup so
these are sort of non-deterministic
events that may happen so the designers
had to sit down and like figure out what
they all work and here are the ones
here's the kind of stuff they talked
about so one is inputs from external
sources like clients which arrive just
whenever they arrive right they're not
predictable there are no sense in which
the time at which a client request
arrives or its content is a
deterministic function of the services
state because it's not so these actually
this system is really dedicated to a
world in which services only talk over
the network and so the only really
basically the only form of input or
output in this system is supported by
this system seems to be network packets
coming and going so we didn't put
arrives at what that really means it's a
packet
arrives and what a packet really
consists of for us is the data in the
packet plus the interrupt
that's signaled that the packet had
arrived so that's quite important so
when a packet arrives
I'm ordinarily the NIC DMAs the packet
contents into memory and then raises an
interrupt which the operating system
feels and the interrupt happens at some
point in the instruction stream and so
both of those have to look identical on
the primary and backup or else we're
gonna have they're also executions gonna
diverge and so you know the real issue
is when the interrupt occurs exactly at
which instruction the interrupts happen
to occur and better be the same on the
primary in the backup otherwise their
execution is different and their states
are gonna diverge and so we care about
the content of the packet and the timing
of the interrupt and then as a couple of
people have mentioned there's a few
instructions that that behave
differently on different computers or
differently depending on something like
there's maybe a random number generator
instruction there's I get time-of-day
instructions that will yield different
answers have called at different times
and unique ID instructions another huge
source of non determinism which the
paper basically rules out is multi-core
parallelism this is a uni-process only
system there's no multi-core in this
world the reason for this is that if it
allowed multi-core then then the service
would be running on multiple cores and
the instructions of the service the rest
of you know the different cores are
interleaved in some way which is not
predictable and so really if we run the
same code on the on the backup in the
server if it's parallel code running on
a multi-core the tube interleave the
instructions in the two cores in
different ways the hardware will and
that can just cause
different results because you know
supposing the code and the two cores you
know they both asked for a lock on some
data well on the master you know
core one may get the lock before core two
on the slave just because of a tiny
timing difference core two may got the
lock first and the you know execution
results are totally different likely to
be totally different if different
threads get the lock
so multi-core is the grim source among
non-determinisms just totally
outlawed in this papers world and indeed
like as far as I can tell the techniques
are not really applicable the service
不能使用多核并行
can't use multi-core parallel parallelism
硬件几乎可以肯定是多核并行的
the hardware is almost
certainly multi-core parallel
但那是虚拟机monitor下面的硬件
but that's the hardware sitting underneath the
virtual machine monitor
虚拟机monitor提供给guest操作系统的
the machine that the virtual machine monitor exposes to
one of the guest operating systems that
运行primary和backup的虚拟机
runs the primary backup that emulated
virtual machine is a unicore
是单核机器（在这篇论文中）
is a uni-processor machine in this paper
我猜他们没有一个简单的方法
and I'm guessing there's not an easy way for them
可以使这种设计应用于多核虚拟机
to adapt this design to multi-core
virtual machines
好的，这些是
okay so these are really
经过logging channel的这些事件
it's these events that go over the logging channel
日志记录的格式
and so the format of a log record
他们没有说清楚
a log entry they don't quite say
但我猜想日志条目中要有三样东西
but I'm guessing that there's
really three things in a log entry
（一是）事件发生时的指令号
the instruction number at which
the event occurred
因为如果您要传送中断或输入，或别的
because if you're delivering an interrupt or
input or whatever it better be delivered
最好将其传送到primary和backup中完全相同的位置
at exactly the same place in the primary and backup
所以我们需要知道
so we need to know the
指令序号
instruction number and by instruction number
指令序号的意思是
I mean the number of
自机器启动以来的指令数量
instructions since the machine booted
而不是指令地址
not the instruction address but like
例如，执行机器启动以来第40亿零79条指令
oh we're executing the four billion and
79th instructions since boot
所以日志条目将包含指令序号
so log entry is gonna have an instruction number
对于中断和输入
for an interrupt, for input it's
它将是中断在primary发生时的指令序号
going to be the instruction at which the
interrupt was delivered on the primary
对于一个怪异指令 比如获取一天中的时间
and for a weird instruction like get time of day
这个序号是
it's going to be the
获取时间的指令的指令序号
instruction number of the instruction of
the get time of day or whatever instruction
或者无论什么指令在primary上执行的序号
that was executed on the primary
这样backup就知道在哪里让此事件发生
so that the backup
knows where to where to call this event to occur
好的，（日志条目）会有type
okay so there's gonna be a type
网络输入，或者怪异指令
network input whatever, weird instruction
然后（日志条目）会有data
and then there's gonna be data
如果是有数据包到达，
for a packet arrival it's gonna
data会是包里的数据
be the packet data, for one of these
对于怪异指令，data将是这些怪异指令
weird instructions it's going to be the
在primary上执行后的结果
result of the instruction
when it was executed on the primary
这样备份虚拟机就可以伪造指令
so that the backup virtual machine can sort of
然后提供相同的结果
fake the instruction and supply that same
result
好的
okay so as an example the
这两个操作系统，guest操作系统
both of these operating systems guest operating system
假定要求硬件
assumes requires that the
这里是仿真的硬件，虚拟机
hardware in this case emulated hardware
其计时器每秒滴答一百次
virtual machine has a timer that ticks
say a hundred times a second
并产生中断给操作系统
and causes interrupts to the operating system and
这就是操作系统通过
that's how the operating system keeps
计数计时器中断来跟踪其时间的方式
track of time it's by counting these timer interrupts
因此
so the way that plays
因此计时器必须
out here, so the timers have to
在primary，backup中的完全相同的位置产生中断
happen at exactly the same place in the primary and backup
否则他们不会执行相同的，并且分歧
otherwise they don't
execute the same and diverge
实际情况是
so what really happens is that
在运行FT虚拟机monitor的物理机上有一个计时器
there's a timer on the physical machine
that's running the FT virtual machine monitor
物理机器上的计时器计时并发出中断
and the timer on the physical
物理机上的计时器计时并发出中断
machine ticks and delivers an interrupt
将计时器中断传递给primary上的虚拟机monitor
a timer interrupt to the virtual machine
monitor on the primary
虚拟机monitor在适当的时候停止primary的执行
the virtual machine monitor at the
appropriate moment stops the execution of the primary
记下自启动以来的指令序号
writes down the
instruction number that it was at
记下自启动以来的指令序号
instruction since boot
然后以该指令编号将伪造的模拟和中断
and then delivers sort of fake emulates and
interrupts into the guest operating
提供给primary中的guest操作系统
system in the primary at that
instruction number
你仿真的计时器硬件刚刚滴答了
saying oh you know you're emulating the timer hardware just
有中断
ticked there's the interrupt
然后
and then the
然后primary虚拟机monitor
primary virtual machine monitor sends
将中断发生的指令号发送给backup
that instruction number which the
interrupt happened to the backup
backup当然
the backup of course it's virtual
其虚拟机monitor
machine monitor is also taking timer
也从其物理计时器获取计时器中断
interrupts from its physical timer
并没有给提供
and it's not giving them it's not giving
没有把真的物理计时器中断传递给backup操作系统
its real physical timer interrupts
它忽略了它们
to the backup operating system. it's just ignoring them
当primary计时器中断的日志条目到达此处
when the
log entry for the primary's timer
当primary计时器中断的日志条目到达此处
interrupts arrives here
然后backup虚拟机monitor将与CPU配合
then the backup virtual machine monitor will arrange
这需要特殊的CPU支持
with the CPU and this requires special
CPU support to cause the physical
以使物理机在与primary相同的指令序号处中断
machine to interrupt at the same
instruction number
以使物理机在与primary相同的指令序号处中断
at the timer interrupts tapped into the primary
此时，虚拟机monitor再次从guest操作系统取回控制
at that point the virtual
machine monitor gets control again from the guest
然后用伪造的计时器中断
and then fakes the timer
交给backup操作系统
interrupts into the backup operating system
现在的指令号与主指令上的指令号完全相同
now exactly the same
instruction number as it occurred on the primary
是的，这个观察是
well yeah so the observation is
这依赖于CPU中有一些特殊的硬件
that this relies on the CPU
having some special hardware in it
因此虚拟机monitor可以告诉硬件，CPU
where the vmm can tell the hardware， CPU please
请从现在开始的第一千条指令处中断
interrupt a thousand instructions from now
然后是虚拟机monitor
and then the vmm where so that
它会在与primary相同的指令序号处中断
it'll interrupt at the
它会在与primary相同的中断序号处发生中断
right instruction number the same
instruction as the primary did
然后虚拟机monitor告诉CPU
and then the vmm just tells the cpu to
恢复backup的执行
resume executing again in the backup
恰好在一千条指令之后
and exactly a thousand instructions later
CPU会强制将中断虚拟机monitor
the CPU will force an interrupt into the
virtual machine monitor
这是特殊的硬件
and that that's special hardware but it turns out it's
但是所有英特尔芯片上有，因此它不是
on all Intel chips so it's not
那么特别
it's not that special anymore
放在15年前，它还挺新鲜的，现在完全是常规操作
15 years ago it was exotic now it's totally normal
而且
and it turns out there's
它还有很多其他用途，例如
a lot of other uses for it like um if
如果您想进行性能分析
you want to do profiling you wanna do
您想做CPU时间性能分析
CPU time profiling what you'd really like
执行CPU时间分析的一种方法
or one way to do CPU time profiling
是让微处理器每千条指令中断一次
is to have the microprocessor interrupt
every thousand instructions right
这里用的是相同的硬件
and this is the hardware that's this
是和让微处理器每千条指令产生一个中断的相同的硬件
Hardware also this is the same hardware
that would cause the microprocessor to
是和让微处理器每千条指令产生一个中断的相同的硬件
generate an interrupt every thousand instructions
所以这是你的CPU中非常自然的小工具
so it's a very natural sort
of gadget to want in your CPU
好的，是的
all right yes
如果backup领先primary怎么办
what if the backup gets ahead of the primary
我们知道
we standing above
primary即将在第一百万条指令处中断
know that the primary is
about to take an interrupt at the millionth instruction
但是备份已经执行了第一百万零一条指令
but the backup has
already executed the million
但是备份已经执行了第一百万零一条指令
and first instruction
如果我们允许这种情况发生
if we let this happen it's gonna be too
那么传递中断将为时已晚
late to deliver the interrupts
如果我们允许backup领先primary执行
if we let the backup execute ahead of the primary
就来不及将中断放在
it's going to be too late to deliver the
primary指令流和backup指令流的相同位置
interrupts at the same point in the
primary instruction stream and the
primary指令流和backup指令流的相同位置
backup instruction stream
所以我们不能让这种情况发生
so we cannot let that happen we cannot let the
我们不能让backup在执行中领先于primary
backup get ahead of the primary in execution
而VMware FT实现这一亩地的方式
and the way VMware FT does
就是backup虚拟机monitor
that is that the backup virtual machine monitor
实际上维护一个缓冲区
actually keeps a
存放来自primary的等待执行的事件
buffer of waiting events that have
arrived from the primary
它不会让backup执行
and it will not let the backup execute unless
除非该缓冲区中至少有一个事件
there's at least one event in that buffer
如果该缓冲区中有一个事件
and if there's one event in that buffer
那么它将根据指令编号，知道强制停止backup执行的位置
then it will know from the instruction number
the place at which it's got a force the
那么它将根据指令编号，知道强制停止backup执行的位置
backup to stop executing
因此，任何时候当backup在执行时
so always the backup is executing with the
CPU总是已经被告知下一个停止的时间点
CPU being told exactly where the next
即下一个停止的指令序号
stopping point the next instruction
number of a stopping point is
只有在buffer中有事件，告诉其下一步停止的地方时
because the backup only executes if it has an
backup才会执行
event here that tells it where to stop next
所以这意味着它会在primary之后
so that means it starts up after the primary
因为backup甚至不能开始执行，直到primary
because the backup can't
even start executing until the primary
产生了第一个事件，并且该事件已经到达backup
has generated the first event
and that event has arrived at the backup
因此backup总是落后primary一个事件
so the backup sort of always one event
落后primary至少一个事件
basically behind the at least one event
behind the primary
如果由于某种原因而变慢
and if it's slower for some other whatever reason maybe
可能是该物理机器上正在运行其他内容
there's other stuff running on that
physical machine
那么backup可能落后primary多个事件
then the backup might get multiple events behind
the primary
对于到达特定数据包的情况，通常会有一点复杂
alright there's a one little piece of
mess about arriving the specific case of arriving packets
通常地，当一个
ordinarily when a
数据包从网络接口卡到达
packet arrives from a network interface card
如果我们没有运行虚拟机
if we weren't running a virtual machine
网络接口卡会
the network interface card would
通过DMA方式将数据包内容传到它所在计算机的内存中
DMA(Direct Memory Access) the packet content into the memory
of the computer that it's attached to
当数据从网络接口卡到达时
sort of as the data arrives from the
network interface card
你可能没有编写过这样的软件
and that means you should never write software like this
但有可能，计算机上运行的操作系统
but it could be that the
但可能是计算机上运行的操作系统
operating system that's running on a
可能会看到包中的数据
computer might actually see the data of
当数据被从网络接口卡DMA或拷贝到内存时
a packet as its DMA or copied from the
network interface card into memory right
我们不知道运行的是什么操作系统
this is and you know we don't
这个系统（VMM）被设计以支持任何操作系统
know what operating this system is
designed so that it can support any operating system
可能有一个操作系统
and gosh maybe there is
an operating system that watches
当它们被复制到内存中时，观察到内存中到达的数据包
arriving packets in memory as they're
copied into memory
所以我们不能让这种情况发生
so we can't let that happen
如果在主节点用的是这种方式
because if the primary happens to be playing that trick
它就会观察到
it's gonna see
如果我们允许网卡直接将接收到的包DMA到主节点内存
you know if we allowed the network interface card to directly DMA incoming packets into the memory of the primary
我们没办法精确控制网卡将数据复制到内存的时间点
the primary we don't have any control over the exact timing of
所以我们也不知道 什么时候主节点观察到网络包中的数据
and so we're not going to know sort of at what times the primary did or didn't observe data from the packet arriving
这就意味着网卡复制包进虚拟机监视器的虚拟内存
and so what that means is that in fact the NIC copies incoming packets into private memory of the virtual machine monitor
然后打断虚拟机监视器告诉它有抵达的包
and then the network interface card interrupts the virtual machine monitor and says oh a packet has arrived
这时虚拟机监视器就会中断主节点
at that point the virtual machine monitor will suspend the primary
记住当前位置的指令号
and remember what instruction number had suspended at
在主节点中断的时候 复制整个包到主节点的内存
copy the entire packet into the primaries memory while the primary suspended and not looking at this copy
然后模拟主节点的网卡中断
and then emulate a network interface card interrupt into the primary
然后发送包和中断位置的指令号到副节点
and then send the packet and the instruction number to the backup
副节点也会中断
the backup will also suspend the backup rope
副节点也会在同样的指令号位置中断
you know virtual machine monitor will spend the backup at that instruction number
复制整个包到副节点的内存 同样副节点中断没有注意包的抵达过程
copy the entire packet and again to the back-up is guaranteed not to be watching the data arrive
然后模拟副节点在同样指令号位置中断
and then fakin interrupts at the same instruction numbers of the primary
这就是论文中描述的回弹缓冲机制
and this is the something the bounce buffer mechanism explained in the paper
会产生记录通道流量的指令都是不寻常的指令 很少见
okay yeah the the only instructions and that result in logging channel traffic or are weird instructions which are rare
一般是在主节点和副节点执行结果会不同的指令
no its instructions that might yield a different result if executed on the primary and backup
例如获取当前时间 获取当前处理器数量
like instruction to get the current time of day or current processor number
或者获取已执行的指令数量
or ask how many instructions have been executed or
这些相对来说都是很少见的
and those actually turn out to be relatively rare
或者说像生成随机数
there's also one them to get random tasks when some machines
让硬件生成用于加密的随机数之类的
to ask or a hardware generated random number for cryptography or something
这些都不是日常的指令
and but those are not everyday instructions
大多数指令例如相加的指令会在主副节点有相同的结果
most instructions like add instructions they're gonna get the same result on primary and backup
没错 每个网络包都被直接打包转发没有修改
exactly right each network packet just it's packaged up and forwarded as it is as a network packet
由两边的TCP/IP栈进行解析
and is interpreted by the tcp/ip stack on both you know
所以我认为99.99%的记录通道流量都是来自于接收到的包
so I'm expecting 99.99% of the logging channel traffic to be incoming packets
只有少部分是因为会产生不确定结果的指令造成
and only a tiny fraction to be results from special non-deterministic instructions
所以我们可以猜到在有客户端连接的服务器上 流量大概是什么样子的
and so we can kind of guess what the traffic load is likely to be for for a server that serves clients
基本就是各个客户端发的包
basically it's a copy of every client packet
所以我们就能估算出记录通道需要有怎样的性能
and then we'll sort of know what the logging channel how fast the logging channel has to be
输出是如何工作的也值得讲一下
it's worth talking a little bit about how output works
在这个系统中 输出就是指发送数据包
and in this system really the only what output basically means only is sending packets
客户端发送请求的网络包 服务端响应网络包
that client send requests in as network packets the response goes back out as network packets
没有其他形式的输出了
and there's really no other form of output
主节点和副节点计算他们要发送的数据包
as I mentioned the you know both primary and backup compute the output packet they want to send
在主节点上真正进行发送
and that sort of asks that simulated mix to send the packet it's really sent on the primary
副节点的包则被简单地丢弃掉
and simply discard it the output packet discarded on the backup
真实的情况会稍微复杂一点
okay but it turns out is a little more complicated than that
假设我们在跑的是一个简单的数据库服务器
so supposing we're what we're running is a some sort of simple database server
服务器支持客户端进行计数器自增（Increment)操作
and the operation the client operation that our database server supports is increment
客户端发送自增的请求 服务端对计数器进行加操作 返回操作后的值
and ideas the client sends an increment requests the database server increments the value and sends back the new value
假设在主节点一切都正常
so maybe on the primary well let's say everything's fine so far
主副节点现在都存有计数器值10在内存中
and the primary backup both have value 10 in memory and that's the current value at the counter
本地网络的客户端发送自增请求到主节点
and some client on the local area network sends a you know an increment request
这个网络包被发到主节点
to the primary that packet is you know delivered to the primary it's you know
然后被主节点的程序执行
it's executed the primary server software and the primary
比如说现在是10 我要将他变为11
says oh you know current values 10 I'm gonna change to 11
然后产生回复告诉客户端结果11
and send a you know response packet back to the client saying saying 11
这个请求也会被发送到副本上 将10改为11
mentioned gonna supposed to be sent to the backup will also be processed here it's going to change this 10 to 11 also
然后同样产生一个回复 并被丢弃掉 理论上是这样
generate a reply and we'll throw it away that's what's supposed to happen the output
然而你也要想一下如果在不恰当的时间服务出现失败会怎么样
however you also need to ask yourself what happens if there's a failure at an awkward time
上这门课的期间你要一直这样问自己
if you should always in this class should always ask yourself
何时出现失败是最坏的情况 这种情况下会发生什么
what's the most awkward time to have a failure and what would happen you to failure occurred then so
假设主节点确实生成了返回给客户端的回复
suppose the primary does indeed generate the reply here back to the client
但是主节点在发送完回复之后就宕机了
but the client the primary crashes just after sending the report its reply to the client
更糟的是 网络向来不保证数据包能传递到接收方
and furthermore and much worse it turns out that you know this is just a network it doesn't guarantee to deliver packets
再假设记录通道也在主节点宕机的时候失效了
let's suppose this log entry on the logging channel got dropped also when the when the primary died
那么现在的状态就是 客户端收到回复11
so now the state of play is the client received a reply saying 11
但是副节点没有收到转发来的客户端请求 所以计数器仍然是10
but the backup did not get the client request so its state is still 10
现在因为察觉到主节点宕机 副节点接管服务
no now the backup takes over because it's seized the primary is dead and
那这个或者其他客户端发送自增请求到原来的副节点
this client or maybe some other client sends an increment request a new backup
当收到请求的时候这个接管工作的副节点开始处理
and now it's really processing these requests and so the new backup when it gets the next increment requests
将计数器从10自增为11
you know it's now going to change its state to 11
然后值11就会第二次作为回复出现
and generate a second 11 response
回复给原来的客户端或者不同的客户端
maybe the same client maybe to a different client
客户端如果比较会发现这是同样的回复 这本不应该发生
which if the clients compare notes or if it's the same client it's just obviously cannot have happened I didn't
因为我们需要支撑的程序在没改动的情况下
so you know because we have to support unmodified software that does not damn
并不能处理这些副节点上不寻常的问题
that there's any funny business of replication going on
意思是我们不能对它进行修改
that means we do not have the opportunity to
比如说我们可以
you know you can imagine the client could go
把客户端改成能处理
you know we could change the client to realize
副节点容错性带来的问题
something funny it happened with the fault tolerance and do I don't know what
但是实际上我们没有这种选择
but we don't have that option here
因为这个系统只有在我们不需要客户端进行改动的情况下才有意义
because this whole system really only makes sense if we're running unmodified software
所以这是个灾难
so so this was a big this is a disaster
我们不能让它发生
we can't have let this happen does
有人记得论文上是怎么样防止它发生的吗？
anybody remember from the paper how they prevent this from happening
输出规则 对的
the output rule yeah so you want to do you know
没错解决的方案就是控制输出规则
yeah so the output rules is the their solution to this problem
方案就是阻止输出
and the idea is that the client he's not allowed to generate you know and
在主节点上不允许生成任何输出
generate any output the primary's not allowed to generate any output
比如我们现在说的这个计数器输出
and what we're talking about now is this output here
直到副节点确认收到了所有的记录
until the backup acknowledges that it has received all log records up to this point
所以整个流程正确的顺序是 回到主节点宕机之前
so the real sequence at the primary then let's now undone crash the primary
回到计数器还是10的时候
go back to them starting at 10 the
正确的顺序是 在这个输出规则下
real sequence now when the output rule is that
当输入到来时
the input arrives at the time the input arrives
虚拟机监视器发送输入的副本到副节点
that's when the virtual machine monitor sends a copy of the input to the backup
这个输入的日志信息
so the the sort of time at which this log message with the input
在主节点产生输出前发到副节点
is sent is before strictly before the primary generates the output sort of obvious
发送之后这个日志就在去往副节点的网络中
then after firing this log entry off across a network and now it's heading towards the backup
这个日志有可能丢失
but I'd have been lost might not
虚拟机监视器同样传递请求到主节点 生成输出
the virtual machine monitor delivers a request to the primary server software it generates the output
所以现在主节点生成结果 计数器值变为11
so now the replicated you know the primary has actually generated change the state 211
然后产生一个11的回复
and generated an output packet that says eleven
但是虚拟机监视器说等一下 现在还不允许生成输出
but the virtual machine monitor says oh wait a minute we're not allowed to generate that output
直到之前的日志记录都被副节点确认
until all previous log records have been acknowledged by the backup
这是最近的一条日志消息
so you know this is the most recent previous log message
所以输出都被虚拟机监视器截停
so this output is held by the virtual machine monitor
直到这条包含客户端输入的日志
until the this log entry containing the input packet from the client
被虚拟机监视器投递和缓冲
is delivered to the virtual machine monitor and buffered by the virtual machine monitor
但是不一定马上会执行
but do not necessarily execute it
可能需要等待副节点执行到指令流中对应的位置
it may be just waiting for the backup to get to that point in the instruction stream
到这里虚拟机监视器就会发送一个ACK包说自己收到输入
and then the virtual machine monitor here will send an ACK packet back saying yes I did get that input
直到主节点接收到ACK包时
and when the acknowledgment comes back
虚拟机监视器才会将包发送到网络中
only then will the virtual machine monitor here release the packet out onto the network
所以这个方案就是 若客户端可以收到回复
and so the idea is that if the client could have seen the reply
那么副节点肯定也收到过请求 并且至少已经存到缓冲区
then necessarily the backup must have seen the request and at least buffered it
因此我们不在会有以下的异常
and so we no longer get this weird situation
客户端已经收到了回复 然后因为有故障发生
in which a client can see a reply but then there's a failure and a cut over
副节点完全没有接到过相关内容
and the replica didn't know anything about that reply
比如说有些情况消息可能会中途丢失
if the you know there's also a situation maybe this message was lost
日志记录丢失后主节点宕机
and if this log entry was lost and then the primary crashes
因为消息没投递成功 所以副节点也没有确认
well since it hadn't been delivered so the backup hadn't sent the ACK
如果主节点宕机
that means if the primary crashed
日志记录随主节点宕机丢失
this log entry was brought in the primary crashed
它肯定在虚拟机监视器发送输出包之前丢失
it must have crashed before the virtual machine monitor release the output packet
客户端不可能提前收到回复
and for this client couldn't have gotten the reply
它们也不会识别出异常发生
and so it's not in a position to spot any irregularities
所以我们需要有输出规则进行限制
there we have the output rule
brennon see
我不了解 论文没有谈到虚拟机监视器的实现
I don't know paper doesn't mention how the virtual machine monitor is implemented
这是非常底层的知识
I mean it's pretty low level stuff because
像划分内存空间 计算页表
it's sitting there allocating memory and figuring page tables
与设备驱动交互 拦截指令
and talking to device drivers and intercepting instructions
搞明白Guest用户执行的命令等
and understanding what instructions the guest was executing
所以这是一些底层的东西 一般用C或C++编写的
so we're talking about low-level stuff what language is written in traditionally C or C++
但我并不了解
but I don't actually know
回到这里 主节点需要延迟回复
okay this of the primary has to delay at this point
先等副节点确认已经收到最新消息
waiting for the backup to say that it's up to date
这是几乎所有主备复制模式性能的一道坎
this is a real performance thorn in the side of just about every replication scheme
这种同步等待让主节点不会领先于副节点太多
this sort of synchronous wait where the we can't let the primary get too far ahead of the backup
因为如果主节点在领先的情况下出现故障
because if the primary failed while it was ahead
副节点就会出现数据延迟
that would be the backup lagging
副节点的进度和客户端会不一致
lagging behind clients right
所以每种主备系统都有这样的问题
so just about every replication system has this problem that
某个时间主节点必须等待副节点
at some point the primary has to stall waiting for the backup
这是对性能实打实的限制
and it's a real limit on performance
即使机器是在相邻机架上
even if the machines are like side-by-side and adjacent racks
主节点发送消息和接收确认
it's still you know we're talking about a half a millisecond or something
仍然需要等上0.5毫秒
to send messages back and forth with a primary stalled
如果说像避免像地震 大范围断电等问题
and if we wanna like withstand earthquakes or citywide power failures
主副节点必须位于不同的城市
you know the primary in the backup have to be in different cities
那延迟大概会增加到5毫秒
that's probably five milliseconds apart
如果我们主副节点在不同城市进行复制
every time we produce output if we replicate in the two replicas in different city
每一个发送的包
every packet that it produces this output
都需要等上5毫秒让日志记录到达副节点上
has to first wait the five milliseconds or whatever to have the last log entry get to the backup
然后响应确认 最后才能发送回复给客户端
and have the acknowledgment come back and then we can release a path packet
对于一些可靠性要求低的服务 可能并不成问题
and you know for sort of low intensity services that's not a problem
但是对于一些数据库服务
but if we're building a you know database server that we would like to
比如需要每秒处理百万请求
you know that if it weren't for this could process millions of requests per second
那将会对性能有极大的影响
then that's just unbelievably damaging for performance
这也时在条件允许的情况下
and this is a big reason why people you know
人们会使用一些不同的主副复制模式
if they possibly can use a replication scheme
比如说在更高层次操作 并且需要解析操作内容
that's operating at a higher level and kind of understands the semantics of operations
然后不需要每个包都等待确认
and so it doesn't have to stall on every packet
比如只在进行高层次操作时才等待
you know it could stall on every high level operation or even notice that well
只读操作完全不需要等待
you know read-only operations don't have to stall at all
只需要等待写操作同步或者其他一些操作
it's only write or just stall at something
但你需要在应用层上实现这些区分
but you have to there has to be an application level replication scheme to to realize that
你说的都是对的
you're absolutely right
虚拟机监视器不需要阻止主节点执行命令
so the observation is that you don't have to stall the execution of the primary
只需要阻止输出就好
you only have to hold the output
这可能可以做得更好
and so maybe that's not as bad as it could be
但至少这样在一个服务中
but nevertheless it means that every you know in a service
可以在几微秒内响应客户端
that could otherwise have responded in a couple of microseconds to the client
如果我们要先等待处于另一个城市的副节点响应
you know if we have to first update the replicas in the next city
那可能会让10微秒变成10毫秒
we turn to you know 10 micro second interaction into it 10 millisecond interactions possibly
如果你有大量客户端并发请求
if you have vast numbers of clients submitting concurrent requests
虽然可能在高延迟下完成大量处理
then you may may be able to maintain high throughput even with high latency
但是你需要非常巧妙的设计才能做到
but you have to be lucky to or very clever designer to get that
这是个很好的想法
that's a great idea
但是如果你将消息记录到主节点内存中
but if you log in the memory of the primary
在主节点宕机时日志就会丢失
that log will disappear when the primary crashes
通常认为服务器失效就意味着
or that's usual semantics of a server failing is that
服务器内存中的内容都会丢失
you lose everything inside the box like the contents of memory
或者即使你不会如此
or you know if even if you didn't
比如说失效是因为主节点电源被意外拔掉
if the failure is that somebody unplugged the power cable accidentally from the primary
但你有备用电源之类
even if the primary just has battery backed up RAM or I don't know what
你也做不到
you can't get at it
副节点也做不到如此
all right the backup can't get at it
实际上系统在副节点的内存中记录了输出
so in fact this system does log the output and the place it logs it is in the memory of the backup
为了保证可靠记录 你必须遵守输出规则 等待确认
and in order to reliably log it there you have to observe the output rule and wait for the acknowledgment
所以这是个正确的想法 但是不能使用主节点内存来做
so it's entirely correct idea just can't use the primary's memory for it
再说一遍?
say it again
这个想法很棒
that's a clever idea I'd
他问的是 能否输入由主节点接收 输出由副节点发送
and so the question is maybe input should go to the primary but output should come from the backup
我完全没有想过
I completely haven't thought this through
这或许可以
that might work that
我不确定 这很有意思
I don't know that's interesting
yeah maybe I will
还有一个可能出现的情况
one possibility this does expose though is that
主节点在输出已经发送出去之后宕机
the situation you know maybe the a primary crashes after its output is released
客户端已经收到回复
so the client does receive the reply
然后主节点宕机
then the primary crashes
副节点的输入还在事件缓冲中
the backups input is still in this event buffer
在副节点的虚拟机监视器种
in the virtual machine monitor of the backup
还没有投递到真正的服务副本
it hasn't been delivered to the actual replicated service
副节点要顶替宕机的主节点
when the backup goes live after the crash of the primary
它首先要消费所有未处理的记录
the backup first has to consume all of the sort of log records that are lying around
以赶上主节点的进度
that it hasn't consumed yet has to catch up to the primary
否则主副节点进度就会不一致
otherwise it won't take over with the same state
副节点在接管服务之前要先消费完记录
so before the backup can go live it actually has to consume all these entries
最后一条记录是客户端的请求
the last entry is presumably is the request from the client
副节点会在它之后开始接管服务
so the backup will be live after after it
在传递客户端请求的中断之后
after the interrupt that delivers the request from the client
这意味着副节点计数器自增到11
and that means that the backup well you know increment its counter to eleven
然后生成一个输出包 因为这时候它接管服务
and then generate an output packet and since it's live at this point
所以生成输出 客户端会受到两个11回复
it will generate the output packet and the client will get two eleven replies
如果真的发生这种情况的话是不对的
which is also if it if that really happened would be anomalous
如果是单服务器的话这不应该发生
like possibly not something that could happen if there was only one server
好消息则是
the good news is that almost certainly
如果服务间是使用TCP通信
or the almost certainly the client is talking to this service using TCP
请求和响应都是通过TCP通道传输
and that this is the request and the response go back and forth on a TCP Channel
当副节点接管时
the when the backup takes over
副节点的状态和主节点一致 知道所有TCP连接
the backup since the state is identical to the primaries it knows all about that TCP connection
还有所有的序列号
and whether all the sequence numbers are and whatnot
当它产生这个包时
and when it generates this packet
它会产生和原来的包一样的序列号
it will generate it with the same TCP sequence number as an original packet
客户端的TCP栈会认为这是个重复的包
and the TCP stack on the client will say oh wait a minute that's a duplicate packet
在TCP层就会将它丢弃掉
we'll discard the duplicate packet at the TCP level
而在用户层软件中永远不会看到重复包
and the user level software will just never see this duplicate
所以这个系统中
and so this system really you know
你可以认为问题被意外解决了或者被巧妙处理了
you can view this as a kind of accidental or clever trick
但事实上对于所有能够进行切换的复制系统
but the fact is for any replication system where cutover can happen
也就是大部分的复制系统
which is to say pretty much any replication system
很难将他们设计成
it's essentially impossible to design them
保证切换时不会有重复输出
in a way that they are guaranteed not to generate duplicate output
你可以在两边都引发报错
basically you know you well you can err on either side
然后在两边都不生成输出
I'm not even either not generate the output at all which
但是这种做法很糟糕
would be bad which would be terrible
或者你可以允许切换时有两次输出
or you can generate the output twice on a cutover
总之没有办法可以保证只有一次输出
that's basically no way to generate it guaranteed generated only once
两边都引发报错或者允许可能的重复输出
everybody errors on the side or possibly generating duplicate output
某种程度上说 所有复制模式的客户端
and that means that at some level the client side of all replication schemes
都需要重复包的检测机制
need some sort of duplicate detection scheme
here we get to use TCP s that we didn't have TCP that would have to be something else
maybe application level sequence numbers or I don't know what
and you'll see all of this
and actually you'll see versions of
essentially everything I've talked about like the output rule for example in labs 2 & 3
you'll design your own replicated state machine
yes
yes to the first part
so the scenario is
the primary sends the reply
and then either the primary send the close packet
or the client closes the connect the TCP connection after it receives the primary's reply
so now there's like no connection on the client side
but there is a connection on the backup side
and so now the backup
so the backup consumes the very last log entry that as the input is now live
so we're not responsible for replicating anything at this point right
because the backup now live there's no other replica as the primary died
so there's no like if if we don't if the backup fails to execute in log step with the primary
that's fine actually
because the primary is is dead and we do not want to execute in log step with it
okay so the primer is now not it's live
it generates an output on this TCP connection that isn't closed yet from the backup point of view
this packet arrives with the client on a TCP connection
that doesn't exist anymore from the clients point of view
like no big whoopee on the client right
he's just going to throw away the packet as if nothing happened the application won't no
the client may send a reset
something like a TCP error or whatever packet
back to the backup and the backup does something or other with it
but it doesn't matter b
ecause we're not diverging from anything
because there's no primary to diverge from
you can just handle a stray we said however it likes
and what it'll in fact do is basically ignore
but there's no now the backup has gone live there's just no
we don't owe anybody anything as far as replication
yeah
well you can bet since the backups memory image is identical to the primaries image
that they're sending packets with the very same source TCP number
and they're very same everything
they're sending bit for bit identical packets
you know at this level the server's don't have IP addresses
or for our purposes
the virtual machines you know the primary in the back up virtual machines have IP addresses
but the the physical computer and the vmm are transparent to the network
it's not entirely true but it's basically the case that
the virtual machine monitor in the physical machine
don't really have identity of their own on the network
because you can configure that then that way instead these they're not
you know the virtual machine with a sewing operating system in its own TCP stack
it doesn't IP address underneath there an address and all this other stuff
which is identical between the primary in the backup
and when it sends a packet
it sends it with the virtual machines IP address and Ethernet address
and those bits least in my mental model are just simply passed through on to the local area network
it's exactly what we want
and so I think he doesn't generate exactly the same packets
that the primary would have generated
there's maybe a little bit of trickery you know what the we
if this is these are actually plugged into an Ethernet switch
into the physical machines maybe it wasn't in two different ports of an Ethernet switch
and we'd like the Ethernet switch to change its mind about
which of these two machines that delivers packets with replicated services Ethernet address
and so there's a little bit of funny business there
for the most part they're just generating identical packets
so let me just send them out
okay so another little detail I've been glossing over is that
I've been assuming that the primary just fails or the backup just fails
that is fail stop right
but that's not the only option
another very common situation that has to be dealt with is
if the two machines are still up and running and executing
but there's something funny happen on the network
that causes them not to be able to talk to each other
but to still be able to talk to some clients
so if that happened if the primary backup couldn't talk to each other
but they could still talk to the clients
they would both think oh the other replicas dead
I better take over and go live
and so now we have two machines going live with this service
and now you know they're no longer sending each other log events or anything
they're just diverging
maybe they're accepting different client inputs and changes are stayed in different ways
so now we have a split brain disaster
if we let the primary in the backup go live
because it was a network that has some kind of failure instead of these machines
and the way that this paper solves it I mean
is by appealing to an outside authority to make the decision about
which of the primary of the backup is allowed to be live
and so
it they're you know it turns out that their storage is actually not on local disk
this almost doesn't matter
but their storage is on some external disk server
and as well as being in this server as a like totally separate service
there's nothing to do with disks
there this server happens to abort this test and set
test and set service over the network where you
you can send a test and set request to it
and there's some flag it's keeping in memory
and it'll set the flag and return what the old value was
so both primary and backup have to sort of acquire this test and set flag
it's a little bit like a lock
in order to go live they both may be send test and set requests at the same time
to this test and set server
the first one gets back a reply that says oh the flag used to be zero
now it's one this second request to arrive
the response from the test and set server is
Oh actually the flag was already one when your request arrived
so so basically you're not allowed to be primary
and so this this test and set server
and we can think of it as a single machine
is the arbitrator that decides which of the two should go live
if they both think the other ones dead due to a network partition
any questions about this mechanism
you're busted
yeah if the test and set server should be dead at the critical moment when
and so actually even if there's not a network partition
under all circumstances in which
one or the other of these wants to go live because it thinks the others dead
even when the other one really is dead
the one that wants to collide still has to acquire the test and set lock
because one of like the deep rules of 6.824 game is that
you cannot tell whether or another computer is dead or not
all you know is that you stopped receiving packets from it
and you don't know whether it's because the other computer is dead
or because something has gone wrong with the network between you and the other computer
so all the backup ceases well I've stuck in packets
maybe the primary is dead maybe it's live
primary probably sees the same thing
so if there's a network partition
they certainly have to ask the Test-and-Set server
but since they don't know if it's a network partition
they have to ask the test and set server regardless of whether it's a partition or not
so anytime either wants to collide
the test and set server also has to be alive
because they always have to acquire this test and set lock
so the test and set server sounds like a single point of failure
they were trying to build a replicated fault tolerant whatever thing
but in the end you know we can't failover unless unless this is alive so
that's a bit of a bummer
I'm guessing though
I'm making a strong guess that the test and set server is actually
itself a replicated service and is fault tolerant right
it's almost certainly I mean these people of VMware
where they're like happy to sell you a million dollar highly available storage system
that uses enormous amounts of replication internally
um since the test and set thing is on there dis server
I'm I'm guessing it's replicated too
and the stuff you'll be doing in lab 2 in lab 3 is more than powerful enough
for you to build your own fault-tolerant test and set server
so this problem can easily be eliminated